# michael/smith

michael@eightnine.co / eightnine.co/smith / (404) 661-6558

#### **Professional Focus**

As a front-end developer working out of Chicago I've spent the past six years focusing on architecting & building complex, eye-catching, and scalable React + Redux web apps for a wide variety of clients. I utilize my strong background in visual and interaction design in all my development projects, making sure that the solutions I implement are grounded by time tested UX concepts and meet the accessibility needs of all my clients' users. Having spent years working in the React + Redux stack, I've continued to invest my time into more experimental web features such as service workers and client-side AR as well as competing FE technology like Vue JS.

## **Experience**

#### **Lead Interactive Developer**

2017 — Current

Isobar — Chicago, IL

As a lead developer with Isobar, I've focused primarily on architecting and building React + Redux web applications for the United States Air Force and Enterprise Car Rentals. I've lead numerous projects and feature releases for both clients, and worked to seamlessly coordinate larger cross-discipline team efforts for significant releases and milestones.

### Senior UI Developer

2014 — 2017

Dunn Solutions Group — Skokie, IL

As a senior UI Developer at Dunn Solutions Group I built a wide variety of dynamic, fully responsive portals & e-commerce sites for clients that ranged from global cosmetic companies to hospital chains. I led the front-end development & UI design efforts for many of these projects from inception to completion, working directly with our clients.

## **Graphic Designer**

2013 - 2014

DePaul University's AMD Department — Chicago, IL

As the AMD Department's in house graphic designer I created two identity systems for DePaul's annual art showcases, The I AM I Showcase and the 2014 Senior Capstone Exhibition. Additionally, I designed a wide variety of posters, promotional materials and installation graphics for the AMD Department's faculty and professors.

# **Education**

#### **DePaul University**

2014

Chicago, IL

Bachelor's Degree in Interactive Media — Concentration in Interaction Design